PROFILE

Security professional and USAF veteran with 20+ years' IT experience (including at Battelle and State of Ohio), with 4+ years in security operations, seeks position that requires familiarity with security tools, ability to communicate with all levels of the organization, and experience with the implementation of cyber strategies from inception to execution.

EDUCATION

Embry Riddle Aeronautical University

B.S.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

August 2018 – February 2020 Infinite Contract State of Ohio – Office of Information Security and Privacy Tier 1 Cyber Security Analyst

- Respond to assigned tickets using ServiceNow
- Remediate phishing attacks using Microsoft Defender Advanced Threat Protection, Office 365, and Symantec Management Center
- Use Symantec Web Analytics to allow approved access to Web page URLS
- Assist Tier 2 and Tier 3 with tickets as needed
- Use McAffe ePO to detect malware on servers and desktops
- Use Tanium to troubleshoot infected systems

2015 – 2018 Battelle

Columbus, OH

Network Systems Analyst II (Security Operations Center/Vulnerability Management)

- Scan Network with Nessus Manager and Professional
- Create and monitor Scan schedule
- Build Nessus Agent Groups
- Perform credentialed, Non-credentialed and Agent scans on servers and workstations
- Perform credentialed and Non-Credentialed WAS and DMZ scans
- Perform internal and external Discovery scans
- Work with clients to resolve Nessus plugin scan requirements
- Prioritize network vulnerability threat with Kenna Security
- Monitor Kenna Security Connector tunnel Nessus file upload integrity
- Assign and track ServiceNow vulnerability remediation requests
- Provide vulnerability remediation assistance to server Admins
- Maintain Access Management CMDB
- Create reports for upper management
- Create detailed instructional documentation
- SOC exposure to SIEM tools i.e. Carbon Black (Response and Defense), FireEye,

2013 – 2015 Battelle

Columbus, OH

Network Systems Analyst II (Internal Network)

- Maintain 2FA (RSA Token, Terminal Server and VMware) NIST FISMA and HIPAA environment
- Verify VEEAM backup integrity, create reports and post to SharePoint for client review
- Troubleshoot, install, and remove third party applications
- Troubleshoot network connectivity issues
- Troubleshoot printer issues
- Install updates
- Remediate vulnerabilities
- Familiarity with Microsoft Group Policy objects as it applies to workstations
- Experience with Microsoft Direct Access
- Submit Firewall and Switch RFC
- Assist remote Users
- Create monthly internal network vulnerability report

2006 – 2013 Battelle

Columbus, OH

1

Sr. Comm/Equip Spec III (20,000+ User environment)

RESUME - DAVID BUCHBERGER

2002 - 2006	Arlington Computer Products (Discover Card)	Columbus, OH
	PC Technician (3,500+ User environment)	
2001 - 2002	TEKsystems (Columbia Gas)	Columbus, OH
	PC Technician (1,000+ User environment)	
2000 -2001	National Board of BPVI	Columbus, OH
	Technical Support Specialist (100+ User environment)	
1998 - 2000	United Parcel Service	Columbus, OH
	PC Technician (100+ User environment)	

KEY SKILLS

Communication:

• Able to quickly resolve issues, strong communication skills, and able to maintain professional demeanour in stressful situations

IT:

- Understand packet analysis and networking
- Familiar with incident response lifecycle
- Able to be part of on-call rotation
- Familiarity with Windows, and mobile operating systems

Cyber:

- Previous Information Security experience
- Independent-thinker and self-starter
- Team Player
- Good follow-up skills and attention to detail
- Good customer service skills

Department Interface Experience

- Support Desk
- Desktop and Infrastructure Support
- Testing (Workstation/Server software/hardware configuration)
- Account Management
- Firewall Team
- Security Operations Center (SOC)
- Asset Management
- Vulnerability Management
- Security Engineering
- Governance, Risk Management, and Compliance (GRC)
- Information Security and Compliance Zone (Project Management)
- Patch Management (SCCM)
- Server Admins (Microsoft & Linux)
- SharePoint
- Data Backup/Storage
- Third Party vendors

Certifications:

• ITIL v3, CompTIA A+, MCP, CompTIA Security+, CompTIA CySA+ (in progress)

Other:

- Microsoft Certified Professional
- Microsoft Direct Access
- Nessus Manager and Professional
- McAfee Vulnerability Manager
- SharePoint